清理干净，快，快！
Clean that up, c'mon. Go, go!
督察，这真的太让人难过了
Inspector, I'll eat my heart out.
如果我们昨天在这里，我们一定会把他们打得落花流水！
Had we been here yesterday, we'd have kicked their asses!
看起来他们知道你们不会在这里
Looks like they knew you wouldn't.
- 你听说米利萨夫的事了吗? - 听说了
- Have you heard about Milisav? - Yes.
快点，把那东西移开！
C'mon, move that thing away from here!
你，快点！
You, come on!
感谢你昨天所做的一切
Congratulations for what you did yesterday.
- 我们被耍了 - 真聪明
They screwed us over. Brilliantly.
- 那你打算怎么办? - 我能怎么办？
- So, what are you going to do? - What can I do?
上面下达命令，开始对整个南部的突袭
The orders are here, launch the raids across the south.
同时发生了十起事件，马其顿人攻击了监狱
Ten incidents at the same time, and Macedonians attack the prison.
你我都清楚马其顿人被和尚控制了
We all know that Monk controls the Macedonians. It's all clear.
是的，而且我最想抓住他
It is, and I'd like to catch him more than anything else.
那个卑鄙的家伙，但是都结束了，忘了吧
That scumbag. But it's over, forget about it.
做点别的事: 钓鱼，追女人...
Do something else: go fishing, chase women...
为什么还要打仗呢？
Why fight again?
因为怨恨
Out of spite.
那就自己去做，别指望警队
Then do it on your own. Don't count on gendarmes.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第一季 第八集
BLACK SUN EPISODE 8
马其顿 布科沃
VILLAGE OF BUKOVO, MACEDONIA
南斯拉夫王国
KINGDOM OF SERBS, CROATS, AND SLOVENES
- 发现什么了? - 没什么
- And? - Nothing.
一克都没有？
Not a gram?
不要！
Don't!
中士，要不要坐下玩一局？
Sergeant, shall I deal to you too?
这个游戏需要第三个人
We need the third for the game.
你是在放屁吗? 你这个土匪渣滓！
Are you taking a piss? You bandit scum!
我是一个诚实的商人，去森林里寻找强盗吧
I am an honest trader. Look for your bandits in the forest.
我们布科沃很穷
We are poor, here in Bukovo.
正如一位智者所言:
And as a wise man said:
当时机不好的时候，甚至上帝也会对穷人撒尿
When the times are bad, even God pisses at the poor.
你们就是这么做的，但我们已经习惯了
And that's what you, lot, are doing. But we're used to it.
很穷，对吧？
Poor, right?
我们还会再见到你的，死穷鬼！
We'll be seeing more of you, poor man!
- 集合你的人，我们走! - 走吧！
- Gather your men and let's go! - Come on, gendarmes!
- 看来我们已经脱离险境了 - 是的，过去了，来吧
- Looks like we're out the woods. - Yeah, it's gone. C'mon, deal.
你派德约科维奇去那个鬼地方却什么都没找到
You sent Djolovich to that shithole, and you haven't found anything.
只有2-3公斤的麻醉剂？
Just 2-3 kg of narcotics?
他们是真正的流氓，你也知道他们不是新手
They're real rascals, you know. They weren't born yesterday.
- 我是? - 什么？
- And I was? - What?
别跟我来这套！
Don't give me that!
你当然不是三岁小孩
Of course you weren't born yesterday.
是的，你可能希望你根本没有出生
Yeah, you may wish you weren't born at all.
对不起，将军
I'm sorry, general,
但我必须告诉你，如果我们不完成交易
but I have to tell you this. If we don't close our deal,
很快，我们都会希望自己没有出生
really soon, we may all wish we weren't born at all.
如果你们找不到对市中心的枪击事件
If you don't find me the terrorists
负责的恐怖分子
responsible for the bloodshed in the city centre,
我就在格拉夫尼亚查监狱门前把你吊死
I will hang you by the balls in front of Glavnyacha prison.
当你砍下蛇的头时，它会继续蠕动
When you cut off the snake's head, it continues to wriggle,
但实际上却造不成什么伤害
but it is actually harmless.
你是真傻还是在装傻？
Are you really a fool or you're just pretending?
你看，政客是那些恐怖分子的毒蛇头
You see, the politicians are the snake's head of those terrorists.
一旦我们把那个头砍下来
Once we cut off that head,
就可以把那些小偷和走私犯留在这里一段时间
we can leave the thieves and smugglers to wallow for a while.
当然，我们需要一些时间
Granted, we'll need some time
来接管他们的生意，但我们会轻松处理的
to take over their business, but we'll handle them easily.
没有政客支持，他们很容易成为猎物
With no political backing, they'll be an easy prey.
我要那个阿尔索夫和他疯狂的妹妹！
I want that Hadzi Arsov and his deranged sister!
- 我想的就是他们 - 去和德约科维奇谈谈
- It was them I had in mind. - Go talk to Djolovich
事成之前别回来找我
and don't come back to me until you're done.
等一下
Hold on once second.
你这辈子开过枪吗？
Have you ever fired a gun in your life?
我不能和一个从未开过枪的人做生意
I can't do business with someone who has never fired a shot.
拉伊科！
Rajko!
有什么意义呢？
What's the point?
谁来继承这间酒馆？
Who's going to inherit this tavern?
桑尼，我们打烊了，晚点再来吧
Sonny, we're closed. Come by later.
好吧
Okay.
我们没有孩子，你也没有孩子
We don't have kids, you don't have kids.
总会有人继承的，别担心
Somebody will take it, eventually. Don't worry.
米利亚和我决定了..
Well, we've been talking, Milja and I...
事实上，我们已经考虑了一段时间了
In fact, we've been thinking about it for some time now.
我们想收养一个孤儿
We want to adopt an orphan.
有人可以去爱，在我们离去之后还能记得我们
To have someone to love. And to remember us after we're gone.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think?
我觉得我会成为一个好叔叔
I say I'd make a good uncle.
好吧，让我们为此干一杯! 我得走了
Well, let's drink to that! I must go.
你知道米利亚不想看到我和你的前妻坐在一起
You know that Milja doesn't want to see me with your exes.
你差点就死了
You could have died.
不是那样的，请坐
It wasn't like that. Have a seat.
我不能再这么下去了
I can't do this anymore.
当我看到报纸…
When I saw the newspaper...
我要离开他
I'll leave him.
我想和你在一起，余生都想跟你在一起
I want to be with you. The little time we have left.
他会把孩子给我，他一个人照顾不了他们
He will give me the kids, he cannot take care of them alone.
一两个月后一切都会结束
Everything will be over in a month or two.
你爱我吗，索尼娅？
Do you love me, Sonya?
还是你喜欢我们过去的样子？
Or do you love what we used to be?
所有的苦难发生之前的样子？
Before all the hardships.
这是我的同事斯坦科，这是索尼娅
This is my colleague Stanko. This is Sonya.
- 很高兴见到你，-，我也是
- Nice to meet you. - You too.
- 我得走了回头见 - 好的
- I have to go. See you soon. - Okay.
赖斯博士打来电话
Reiss called.
他从维也纳回来了，想见我们
He has returned from Vienna and wants to meet us.
- 好吧 - 你怎么了？
- Alright. - What's wrong with you?
我搞砸了
I blew it.
我把事情搞砸了，我承认
I blew it really bad. I'll admit everything.
承认什么？
Admit what?
布鲁塞尔 比利时
BRUSSELS, BELGIUM
我希望你现在休息，彼得 · 尼古拉耶维奇
I hope you will rest now, Peter Nikolayevich.
我也希望如此
I hope so, too.
这是 Sasha Sorokin
This is Sasha Sorokin.
你好 Sasha
Hello, Sasha.
从现在起他就是我们的儿子了
He will be our son from now on.
你想告诉我什么，兄弟
You wanted to tell me something, brother.
这需要更多的牺牲,
This will demand more sacrifices,
但我不确定我们现在能处理好
but I'm not sure we can handle it at the moment.
你不是来确认的，你是来领导我们的
You're not here to be sure, you're here to lead us.
我想米里奇先生不会同意的
I think Mr. Mirich won't agree.
我们不应该相信他
We shouldn't trust him.
那个人救了你哥哥的命
That man saved your brother's life.
你怎么能这么天真，凯罗？
How can you be so naive, Kyro?
如果这些人不能从中获利，他们什么也不会做
These people don't do anything if they can't profit from it.
米里奇先生遵守了他所有的诺言
Mr. Mirich kept all his promises.
作为一个交易员，我完全信任他
As a trader, I trust him completely.
凯罗，这不是贸易，这是战争！
Kyro, this is not trade. This is war!
多么激动人心的一天啊，凯罗大师
What an exciting day, Master Kyro.
也许对我来说有点太刺激了
Maybe a bit too exciting for me.
我希望你对我们的住宿满意
I hope you're happy with the accommodation.
我为你离开贝尔格莱德安排了一切
I arranged everything for your departure from Belgrade.
我们哪儿也不去
We're not going anywhere.
- 你说什么?-我们哪儿也不去
- I beg your pardon? - We're not going anywhere.
你是谁? 这个人是谁？
Who are you? Who is this man?
我是我们在这里的原因
I'm the reason we're all here.
你大错特错了我们都是因为我才来的
Well, you're damn wrong. I'm the reason we're all here.
我们在贝尔格莱德还有些未了的事,
We have some unfinished business in Belgrade,
我们需要你的帮助
and we need your help.
听着，孩子，我和凯罗大师做了笔交易,
Look, boy. I made a deal with Master Kyro,
作为一个商人对另一个
as one businessman to another.
- 我和你一点关系都没有-那件事已经结束了
- I've got nothing to do with you. - That business is finished.
现在这是一场革命，我要接管这里
This is a revolution now, and I'm taking over.
你说革命? 真的吗？
Revolution, you say? Really?
凯罗大师，这是真的吗? 这个人是在以你的名义说话吗？
Master Kyro, is that true? Is this man talking in your name?
是的
He is.
好吧，去吧
Alright. Go on.
好的，革命者，让我听听你的声音
Okay, revolutionary, let me hear you.
听着，孩子..
Listen kiddo...
你不是妓女的料
You're not for whores.
她们是诚实的职业女性，有着悲惨的人生故事,
They are honest working women with sad life stories,
你会尽力帮助他们，因为你是个傻瓜，就像我一样
and you'll try to help them, 'cause you're a fool, just like me.
好了，现在别教训我了，你到底帮不帮我？
Okay, don't lecture me now. Are you going to help me or not?
你不需要我的帮助
You don't need my help.
如果你没有不小心杀了那个混蛋,
If you hadn't killed the bastard by accident,
我会故意杀了他
I'd have killed him on purpose.
他是裁缝帮的，那天晚上他们打了我
He's from that Tailor's gang. They beat me up that night.
你帮了我，帮了那些妓女,
You did a favour to me, to the whores,
以及贝尔格莱德的公共安全
and to the public safety in Belgrade.
这是件严肃的事情！
This is a serious thing!
是的，斯塔夫拉死了一百多人
It is. Stavra was killed over a hundred.
明天我去犯罪现场的时候,
When I come to the crime scene tomorrow,
我得出的结论是，这是一个未知的攻击者的行为
I'll conclude that it was an act of an unknown assailant.
然后你就会忘记这一切，回家休息一下
And you'll forget about all this, go home and get some rest.
只是别忘了在“小木桶”和赖斯的会面
Just don't forget the meeting with Reiss at the “Little Barrel”.
你好
Hello.
你竟敢支持他！
Don't you dare support him!
那么，我应该感谢谁给我这个荣誉呢？
So, whom should I thank for this honour?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我给达维多维奇小姐当了好几年的律师,
I've been a lawyer of Miss Davidovich for years,
直到现在，你才给我这次会面增光添彩
and it's only now that you grace me with this meeting.
我敢肯定她告诉过你，我不赞成可能伤害她公司的反抗行为？
I'm sure she told you I disapprove defiance that may harm her company?
这种蔑视肯定是我的错，对吧？
And that defiance must have been my fault, right?
当然，你鼓励了她
Certainly, you've encouraged her
还有其他的，私人恶作剧
in that and other, private shenanigans.
多喜叔叔
Uncle Taki.
我和她的私人恶作剧没有关系
I've nothing to do with her private shenanigans.
达维多维奇小姐显然接受了你的建议
And Miss Davidovich has obviously accepted your advice.
你说得对，我不该打听
You're right, I shouldn't pry.
让我们回到正事上来
Let's get back to business.
Taki 叔叔，如果你想说服我们放弃，那是徒劳的
Uncle Taki, if you wanted to convince us to give up, it's in vain.
恰恰相反，我有权通知你..
On the contrary. I am authorised to inform you...
你可能已经赢了
that you've probably won.
你的商业伙伴和竞争对手负债累累,
Your business partners and rivals are in debt to their eyeballs,
他们没有什么可以给予,
and they have nothing to give,
除了我们银行的股份
except the shares in our bank.
高利贷者对银行不感兴趣
The loan shark is not interested in the bank.
他仍把钱藏在床垫底下
He still keeps his money under the mattress.
所以他想让我给他的床垫加油？
So he wants me to fill up his mattress?
没错
Exactly.
只要支付股票价值10% 的小额费用,
For a small fee of 10% of share value,
你会买下他们所有的股份，银行就是你的了
you will buy out all of them, and the bank will be yours.
- 听起来不错-是的
- Sounds acceptable. - It is.
我们是来和你的律师讨论战术的
We're here to discuss the tactics with your lawyer.
- 我们一起谈判-不他自己来
- We'll negotiate together. - No, he'll do it alone.
- 这是条件之一-我能问问是谁的吗？
- It's one of the conditions. - Whose, if I may ask?
比如说，我的
Mine, for example.
否则，就不会有任何谈判
Otherwise, there won't be any negotiations.
是阿里姆皮耶 · 米里奇
It's Alimpiye Mirich.
你和他有过一些不愉快的谈话
You had some unpleasant conversations with him.
我不希望你伤害那个混蛋的感情
And I wouldn't like you to hurt the bastard's feelings
因为这可能会导致交易失败
as it may cause the deal to fail.
- 至于 Alimpiye Mirich...-没有我你不能进去
- As for Alimpiye Mirich... - You're not going in without me.
所以，你想暗杀我的国王？
So, you'd like to assassinate my king?
没错
Exactly.
听着孩子,
Look, boy,
这个国家也许并不完美,
this country may not be perfect,
它的统治者亚历山大国王陛下也不在
and neither is its ruler, His Royal Majesty King Alexander
统一者，科索沃的复仇者
the Unifier, the Avenger of Kosovo.
但这是我们的
But it's ours.
我是一个爱国者，在那个王国里找到了自己的位置
And I'm a patriot who found his place in that kingdom.
很明显你为什么没有
It's pretty clear why you didn't.
- 没有什么?-找到你的位置了
- Didn't what? - Found your place.
但既然你这么客气地问我
But since you're asking me so nicely
帮你把我的尺子炸成碎片,
to help you blow my ruler into bits,
我感到一种爱国的召唤，要给你找一个地方
I feel a patriotic call to find you a place..
六英尺以下
Six feet under.
看着我！
Look at me!
我应该像杀狗一样把你们全杀了，然后把你们埋在地里
I should kill you all like dogs and bury you in a field.
但就像我说的除了是个爱国者,
But as I said, besides being a patriot,
我也是个生意人
I'm also a businessman. And, you see...
这两种性格在我的内心挣扎
Those two personalities struggle inside me.
有时爱国者胜利，有时贸易者胜利
Sometimes a patriot wins, sometimes a trader.
这次你很幸运,
This time you were lucky,
那个商人赢了
the trader won.
我准备帮助你进行自杀式的冒险
I'm ready to help you in your suicidal venture.
但你得付出代价
But it'll cost you.
那么，我能指望你吗？
So, can I count on you?
你看,
You see,
这么微妙的工作需要
such delicate job requires
从你的组织那里得到一点时间和建议
a little bit of time and advice from your organisation.
我建议有人来找我
I suggest that someone should come to me.
- 我能做吗?-这不是个好主意,
- Can I do it? - That's not a good idea,
因为你是个被通缉的罪犯你妹妹会更好
because you're a wanted criminal. Your sister would be better.
不可能
No way.
夫人，他说得对，理智一点
Dame, the man is right. Be reasonable.
Yovana 留在这里！
Yovana stays here!
我去
I'll go.
太好了，我会派车来接你
Excellent. I'll send a car for you.
我提议干杯
I propose a toast.
凯罗大师，你的那个革命者是个疯子,
Master Kyro, that revolutionary of yours is insane,
我不知道像你这样的人怎么会和这样一个疯子在一起,
and I don't know what a man like you is doing with such a lunatic,
但那是你的事
but that's your thing.
商业和革命不能混为一谈
Business and revolution shouldn't mix.
想想吧
Think about it.
我们为什么不马上杀了他们？
Why didn't we kill them right away?
我想上那个马其顿婊子
I want to fuck that Macedonian whore.
看看这个多漂亮
Look how nice this is.
我们明天要做什么？
What are we going to do tomorrow?
我们去水边好吗？
Shall we go to the water?
你疯了吗，茨维塔？
Are you insane, Tsveta?
你知道黑海有多远吗？
Do you know how far the Black Sea is?
什么海? 我是说河
What sea? I meant the river.
黑海一点也不黑
And the Black Sea is not black at all.
茨维塔，我想看看
Tsveta, I'd like to see it.
我从未见过黑海
I've never seen the Black Sea.
- 很远，你自己说的-那又怎样？
- It's far, you said it yourself. - So what?
我们可能会死在去那里的路上
We could die on the way there.
我随时都可能死去
I could die any minute.
我们饿了... 坐下吃点东西吧
We were hungry... Have a seat and eat something.
我去地窖里拿点酒来
I'll go get some wine from the cellar.
爷爷..
Grandpa...
你知道我是谁吗？
do you know who I am?
别那样跟我说话
Don't talk to me like that.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我杀了一个人
I killed a man.
我把尸体藏起来了
And I hid the body.
聪明
Smart.
总比因为某个傻瓜进监狱好
It's better than to go to prison because of some fool.
你怎么知道他是个傻瓜？
How do you know he was a fool?
如果我犯了错怎么办？
What if I made a mistake?
我不认识那个人，我也不在乎
I didn't know that man and I don't care.
也许你犯了个错误也许你没有,
Maybe you made a mistake, maybe you didn't,
但你是我的
but you're mine.
我的斯坦科
My Stanko.
TOPONICA 精神病院
TOPONICA, mental asylum, SERBIA
塞尔维亚、克罗地亚和斯洛文尼亚王国
KINGDOM OF SERBS, CROATS, AND SLOVENES
谢谢你
Thank you.
跟我说说你的王国
Tell me about that kingdom of yours.
这是一个清晰的地方..
It's a place of clarity...
和宁静..
and tranquillity...
一个遥远的应许之地
a distant, promised land.
很久以前,
Once upon a time,
人类是完美的生物
people were perfect creatures.
想象一下，完美的人们
Imagine that, perfect people
在一个完美的世界里
in a perfect world.
没有仇恨，没有谎言，没有死亡
With no hatred, no lies... No death.
有人称之为天堂,
Some would call it paradise,
但我喜欢叫它图勒,
but I like to call it Thule,
- 就像我们的祖先一样-谁的祖先？
- as our ancestors did. - Whose ancestors?
我们的祖先是至高无上的种族
Our ancestors, the supreme race.
神啊他们是神啊
Gods. They were gods...
直到他们像我一样生病
until they got sick, like I did.
远离世界上最严重的疾病
From the worst disease in the world.
你知道那种病的名字吗？
Do you know the name of that illness?
没有
No.
同情... 同情
Compassion... Compassion.
你认为同情心是一种疾病？
You think that compassion is a disease?
最糟糕的
The worst.
陛下,
Your Majesty,
这些神今天还存在吗？
do these gods exist today?
不，但我们可以再次拥有它们
No, but we could have them again.
因为所有..
Because all...
白人是神的后裔,
white people... are descendants of gods,
但不是所有人..
but not all of them...
可以变成神
can become gods.
你和我我们都知道,
You and I, we know that,
但是其他人必须开悟,
but others have to be enlightened,
必须提醒他们,
They have to be reminded,
以圣物为荣
ennobled with the relics
浸透了我们祖先的鲜血！
soaked in blood of our ancestors!
我不能，我不能，对不起，我不能
I can't, I can't, I'm sorry, I can't.
没关系，陛下
It's all right, Your Majesty.
- 才不是-就是
- It's not. - It is.
我不能再重复了
I can't repeat this anymore.
还有一件事
Just one more thing.
为什么你们的王国和我们的如此不同？
Why is your kingdom so different from ours?
它被照亮
It is illuminated
被一个巨大的黑色太阳
by a big black sun.
- 维也纳怎么样，医生?-很有用
- How was Vienna, doctor? - Useful.
为了使它更有用，我不得不去慕尼黑
And to make it more useful, I had to go to Munich.
安德烈亚斯 · 哈恩是 Arseniye Davidovich 银行的幕后合伙人,
The silent partner in Arseniye Davidovich’s bank is Andreas Hahn,
一个强大而危险的人
a powerful and dangerous man
一个危险而强大的领导者,
and a leader of dangerous and powerful,
疯狂的组织”极北会”
crazy organisation "Thule".
他们在贝尔格莱德建立了一个小组
They established a cell in Belgrade.
图勒？
Thule?
这是一个古老的日耳曼疯子，已经存在很长时间了
It's an old Germanic crackpot that's been around for ages.
它出现，消失，然后再出现
It appears, disappears and then appears again.
它已经传播了十年了
It's been spreading for ten years now.
这对你我来说都很危险
It's very dangerous for me and you.
这是什么意思？
What does that mean?
我们应该让他们杀人？
That we should let them kill people?
不，试着在这里阻止他们一下
No. Try to stop them here for a while.
记住，砍头是他们的传统仪式
And remember, cutting off heads is their traditional ritual.
那个疯子画的标志,
The sign that your lunatic drew,
这是他们最重要的象征，黑太阳
it's their most important symbol, the black sun.
给你
Here you are.
教授，长矛呢？
Professor, what about the lance?
这是你最强也是最危险的牌
That's your strongest and the most dangerous card.
这是他们魔法的核心,
It is central to their magic,
他们相信原件在你手上
and they believe you have the original.
如果你不考虑创意的话,
And if you ask me, originality aside,
应该尽快消失
it should disappear as soon as possible.
普列提科耶奇，塔纳西耶维奇，干杯！
Pletikosich, Tanasiyevich, cheers!
我们仍然需要你，教授
We still need you, professor.
没有多少塞尔维亚人还需要我
There aren't that many Serbs that still need me.
试着自己解决这个问题，你不需要“极北”在这里
Try to solve this on your own, you don't need “Thule” here.
我会设法对付那些在他们自己地盘上的人渣
I'll try to deal with those scum in their own territory.
如果你需要什么，就写信到瑞士给我
Write to me in Switzerland if you need anything.
肉很好吃
The meat was excellent.
谢谢，莱斯先生，听到了吗？
Thanks, Mr. Reiss. Heard that, huh?
这是钥匙，这是酒馆，喝到死为止
Here are the keys, here's the tavern. Drink till you drop dead.
我不能再呆下去了，我有家有老婆！
I can't stay any longer. I have a home and a wife!
为什么我没有淹死在萨瓦家里！
Why didn't I drown in the Sava?!
塔妮..
Tane...
我们自己怎么办？
how are we going to do this on our own?
我们会干掉他们的，好吗
We'll fuck them, alright.
你说巴黎没人让你进去？
Nobody admitted you in Paris, you say?
没有，政府里没有，总参谋部也没有
Nobody. Not in the government, nor in the General Staff.
他们把我送到红十字会的库什内那里
They sent me to some Kouchner from the Red Cross.
但他也在胡说八道
But he was also talking nonsense.
在伦敦呢？
And in London?
连门卫都不让我进去
Not even a doorman admitted me there.
萨沙,
Sasha,
再拿点白兰地来
bring us more cognac.
我们不像法国人，只喝一小口
We are not like French, who only take a sip.
彼得 · 尼古拉耶维奇，你根本不应该喝酒
Peter Nikolayevich, you shouldn't drink at all.
他回来后就一直不舒服，呼吸困难
He's been unwell since he came back. It's hard for him to breathe.
男人们在这里说话
Men are talking here.
谢谢你 Sasha
Thank you, Sasha.
你也是来耍我的吗？
You too came to screw me around?
请坐
Have a seat.
上尉，你知道我与此事无关
Captain, you know I've got nothing to do with that.
也许吧
Maybe.
你从来都不是我们的朋友,
You've never been our friend,
所以你没有理由成为我们的敌人
so you have no reason to be our enemy.
- 恰恰相反-什么你现在是我的朋友了？
- On the contrary. - What, you're my friend now?
抑制热情
Curb the enthusiasm.
但现在你的朋友背叛了你,
But now that your friends betrayed you,
我提供合作
I offer cooperation.
有个和尚接管了你的生意,
Some Monk is taking over your business,
一些混蛋在城里到处杀人
and some scumbags are killing people all over the city.
我猜那些混蛋手上有你要的东西
My guess is, those scumbags have what you're looking for.
你怎么知道我在找什么？
How would you know what I'm looking for?
- 那是我的工作-那又怎样？
- That's my job. - So?
我敢打赌蒙克和那些混蛋
I can bet that Monk and the scumbags
和你以前的朋友一起工作，他们好像是我的老板
work with your former friends, who appear to be my bosses.
- 你能证明吗?-不能
- Can you prove it? - No.
船长..
Captain...
在这场战斗中，除了你，我没有别的盟友
I have no other ally in this fight but you.
- 你在寻求我的帮助?-是的
- You're asking for my help? - Yes.
你指望我相信你？
And you expect me to believe you?
我是警察，我的工作就是归还被盗的财物
I'm a policeman and it's my job to return the stolen property.
我的工作到此为止
My job ends there.
听我说，警察
Listen to me, policeman.
当你完成你的工作,
When you finish your job,
把偷走的东西还给我,
and return what was stolen from me,
我们可以谈谈
we can talk.
在那之前,
Until then,
你可以喝私酿伏特加
you can have a moonshine vodka
因为你关闭了我的夜总会
because you closed my club.
我真的需要你的帮助
I really am asking for your help.
我真的说了我该说的
I really said what I had to say.
去你的伏特加
Screw your vodka.
我想说下午好，但情况不妙
I would say good afternoon, but it's not good.
这就是你抱怨工作的结果
That's what you get when you complain about the work.
当我和每个人都结束后，我可以躺在他们旁边
When I'm done with everyone, I can just lie next to them.
Stanko 又发现一具人头
Stanko, we have another severed head.
- 我知道我听说了 Milisav-不不另一个
- I know, I heard, Milisav. - No, no, the other one.
无名氏他们今天早上把她送来的
Jane Doe. They brought her this morning.
在河边的一个袋子里发现的和紫罗兰一样，奈芙娜 · 米利萨夫
Found in a sack by the river. Same as with Violet, Nevena Milisav.
她被下药了
She has been drugged.
但这一次，凶手留下了一个签名
But this time, the murderer has left a signature.
这是玛拉
This is Mara.
怎么了，你在看什么？
What is it, what are you staring at?
探长先生！
Mr. Inspector!
姑娘们，那个叫斯塔夫拉的混蛋在哪儿？
Girls, where's that piece of shit named Stavra?
他走了，是不是，格齐姆？
He's gone, hasn't he, Gezim?
那个混蛋在哪儿？
Where is that prick?
这附近有很多混蛋，你要哪一个？
Many pricks around here, which one do you want?
那个裁缝，不管你叫他什么？
That Tailor, whatever you call him?
告诉他..
Tell him...
买一套新西装和一个坟墓
to get a new suit and a grave.
他是下一个
He's next.
安东尼奥老板，给我们一些豆子
Boss Antonio, give us some beans.
你他妈的在干什么？
What the fuck are you doing?
我有事要告诉你
I've got something to tell you.
他们杀了那么多人
They killed so many people.
但为什么是她呢？
But why her?
为什么她会被标记？
And why is she marked?
放松点，喝点东西
Take it easy, have something to drink.
现在我知道你喜欢妓女了，我更尊重你了
Now that I know you like whores, I respect you even more.
不，不，斯坦科，别激动! 请冷静！
No, no, Stanko, take it easy! Calm down, please!
住手，冷静点! 没事的！
Stop it, calm down! It's okay!
看看这个孩子! 你越来越亲近我了
Look at this kid! You're getting dear to me.
斯坦科，你显然不能工作
Stanko, you obviously can't work.
请你冷静下来后再回来
Come back when you calm down, please.
不不没关系
No, no, it's fine.
没关系，我很好，对不起，医生
It's okay, I'm fine. I'm sorry, doctor.
- 放松放松-还有什么？
- Easy, easy. - What else is there?
医生和我注意到一些奇怪的现象
The doctor and I noticed something odd.
也许没什么，但是很奇怪
Maybe it's nothing, but it is odd.
玛拉和其他所有受害者
Mara and all other victims
他们的血液里有高剂量的鸦片酊
had a high dosage of laudanum in their blood.
但 Avram 自杀时也是如此
But so did Avram when he killed himself.
- Avram?-是的
Avram? Yes.
怎么做到的？
How?
我看了他的病历，里面有些奇怪的东西
I read his medical record. There are some strange things there.
阿瓦库莫维奇医生开鸦片酊作为镇静剂
Dr. Avakumovich prescribing laudanum as a tranquilliser.
鸦片酊是鸦片的衍生物
Laudanum is an opium derivative.
它会引起幻觉
It causes hallucinations.
药物选择有点奇怪
A little strange choice of medication.
阿瓦库莫维奇
Avakumovich.
但这并不意味着什么，他是个有名的精神病学家
But it doesn't have to mean anything. He's a known psychiatrist.
一个著名的精神病学家仅仅因为他在维也纳学习？
A well-known psychiatrist just because he studied in Vienna?
- 他在维也纳学习?-是的
- He studied in Vienna? - Yes.
医生，我也越来越喜欢你了
Doctor, I like you more and more, too.
博雅纳，照顾玛拉，照顾一切..
Boyana, take care of Mara, of everything...
- 当然-我会付钱的
- Sure. - I'll pay for everything.
没关系
It's alright.
- 再见-斯坦科？
- Goodbye. - Stanko?
斯坦科，你不能这样走！
Stanko, you can't go like that!
你现在喜欢上他了？
You have a crush on him now?
既然他来找你对质，我就神魂颠倒了
Now that he confronted you, I'm head over heels.
你没机会了，他喜欢妓女
You don't have a chance, he likes whores.
幸运的是，有人杀了我的对手
Luckily, somebody killed my rival.
- 这个不错-那个白色更好
- This one's good. - That white is even better.
这是什么？
What is this?
木瓜
A quince.
如果这是温柏，我就是草莓
If this is quince, I'm a strawberry.
你在撒尿，兄弟..
You're taking a piss, bro...
我父亲亲手采摘并蒸馏了它们
My dad picked them and distilled them. With his own hands.
他应该用他的技巧对付你妈妈
He should have used his skills with your mom...
看看你现在的样子
Look how you turned out.
我现在要亲自操他
I am going to fuck him myself now.
混蛋! 他在哪儿? ！
Mothefucker! Where is he?!
把他给我! 那个警察在哪? ！
Give him to me! Where's that copper?!
把他给我! 他在哪儿? ！
Give him to me! Where is he?!
我要操到他死为止！
I'll fuck him until he drops dead!
你在看什么? ! 你让他进来的? ！
What are you looking at?! Did you let him in here?!
你只是在喝酒，你根本不在乎！
You're just boozing, you don't give a fuck!
我们在酒馆里还能干什么？
What else are we to do in a tavern?
这就是为什么那个警察想来就来的原因
That's why that copper walks in here whenever he wants.
好像他有九条命似的！
As if he's got nine lives!
我以为我抓住他了，但是没有，他死而复生了！
I thought I had him, but no. He came back from the dead!
他在玩他的小游戏！
And he's playing his little game!
威胁斯塔夫拉和其他人
Threatening Stavra, and others.
斯塔夫拉来了吗？
Did Stavra show up?
那个混蛋在哪儿？
Where is that piece of shit?
他吃了两盘豆子就走了！
He ate two plates of beans and left!
不过他给你留了这个
He left you this, though.
那是什么？
What is that?
他说你不应该打开它，然后交给你的老板
He said you shouldn't open it, and give it to your boss.
打开它！
Open it!
斯塔夫拉的帽子
Stavra's hat.
他说你是下一个
He says you're next.
你让警察在这里玩,
You let the cops play here,
你一无是处
you're good-for-nothing.
滚开! 混蛋！
Piss off! Motherfuckers!
去死吧！
Drop dead!
去死吧，你们这些混蛋！
Drop dead, you fuckers!
混蛋！
Fuckers!
孩子，你占领了女人！
Kid, you're taking over the women!
- 好的老大-天黑了我们就行动
- Okay, boss. - We'll move when it gets dark.
给我弄点吃的，我饿死了
Get me something to eat. I'm starving.
开始工作
Get to work.
我们去睡觉吧
Please, let's go to bed.
你先去，我马上上来
You go, I'll be right up.
彼佳！
Petya!
去吧，我告诉你
Go, I tell you.
萨沙！
Sasha!
白军，黑男爵,
White Army, black baron,
他们在准备皇帝的宝座
they're preparing the emperor's throne.
但是从苔原到英国海域,
But from tundra to the British seas,
红军是最好的
Red Army is the best there is.
但是... 从苔原... 到... 英国的海洋,
But... from tundra... to the... British seas,
红军..
Red Army...
是最好的
is the best there is.
你知道..
Do you know...
你父亲最后的愿望是什么？
what was your father's last wish?
也许不要杀他？
Maybe not to kill him?
他死得很光荣,
He died an honourable officer,
- 他自杀了-不像你
- he killed himself. - Unlike you.
你在帮我谢谢
Well, you're helping me. Thank you.
他..
He...
希望被葬在一个兄弟般的东正教国家
wanted to be buried in a brotherly orthodox country.
我也想要
I want the same.
我明白，我会转达你的愿望，男爵
I understand. I'll convey your wish, baron.
你走楼梯，跟我来
You take the stairs, you come with me.
谢谢你
Thank you.
小姐，我必须为违背诺言而道歉,
Miss, I must apologize for breaking the promise,
但这是你的错
but it is your fault.
如果有人告诉你你没被邀请,
If someone tells you that you're not invited,
你不该来的
you shouldn't come.
- 你认识这些人?-少管闲事！
- You know these people? - Stay out of it!
你不明白我的意思，小姐，我们不需要你
You didn't understand me, Miss. We don't need you.
我们需要检察官
We need the prosecutor.
你只要从车里出来
You just step out of the car.
- 滚出去!-快点
- Get the fuck out! - Come on.
约旦，把她带进去，温柔点
Yordan, take her inside and be gentle.
把她绑起来，她会咬人的
Tie her up, she can bite.
检察官不应该一个人在后面伤心
The prosecutor shouldn't be alone and sad back there.
陪着他
Keep him company.
- 对不起...-等等
- I'm sorry... - Wait, wait...
Pletikosich 督察来了
Inspector Pletikosich is here.
Pletikosich? 让他进来
Pletikosich? Well, let him in.
请进
Please, come in
我认识你
I know you.
你是报纸上那个年轻英俊的督察，对吗？
You're that young and handsome inspector from the papers, right?
- 是的-请坐
- Yes. - Have a seat.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你怎么知道凶手就是那个可怜的 Avram？
How did you realise that the murderer is that poor Avram?
我知道他是个傻瓜，但是砍头..
I knew he was a fool, but to cut off heads...
- 恭喜-谢谢
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
- 你丈夫在家吗?-不在
- Is your husband at home? - No.
他整天探望病人很明显整晚,
He visits patients all day, and obviously the whole night,
- 在我无聊的时候-真可惜
- while I'm getting bored. - That's a pity.
我很无聊？
That I'm bored?
不，我是说他出去了
No, I meant that he's out.
我在一个案子上需要他的意见
I need his opinion on a case.
别担心，他会很乐意帮你的
Do not worry. He'll gladly help you.
他就是不能拒绝你要来点咖啡吗？
He just can't say “no”. Would you like some coffee?
- Kata!-我赶时间
- Kata! - I'm in a hurry.
探长，我得在我的女朋友面前炫耀一下
Inspector, I have to brag before my girlfriends
我见到了勇敢的探长我马上回来
that I met the brave inspector. I'll be right back.
白兰地加咖啡，给你
Cognac before coffee. Here you are.
谢谢
Thanks.
你结婚了吗？
Are you married?
- 不我没有-天啊你还在等什么？
- No, I'm not. - My God, what're you waiting for?
- 很有趣的画-是的
- Very interesting painting. - Yes.
但是没有签名
But it's not signed.
这是我丈夫最重要的病人送的礼物
It's a gift from my husband's most important patient –
- 乔杰王子-那幅画是他给你的？
- Prince Djordje. - He gave you that painting?
- 是的，他自己画的-是吗？
- Yes. He painted it himself. - He did?
- 是的，他很有才华吧?-的确
- Yes. Isn't he talented? - Indeed.
顺便说一句，他是个很好的人... ... 但是，他病得很重
A very nice man, by the way... But, very sick.
黑日
The Black Sun.
你怎么知道的？
How did you know?
他就是这样命名他的画的
That's how he named his painting.
我想太阳是他黑暗的心灵，仍然照耀着
I guess the sun is his darkened mind that still shines.
我真的得走了，谢谢你，再见
I really have to go now. Thank you and goodbye.
咖啡怎么样？
What about the coffee?
你想从我这里得到什么？
What do you want from me?
他们把沃因带到哪里去了？
Where did they take Voyin?
如果你认为项链在他手上，那你就错了
If you think he has the necklace, you're wrong.
闭嘴，女人! 什么项链？
Shut up, woman! What necklace?
你想从我这得到什么? ！
What do you want from me?!
- 你想要我怎么样? !-我要你安静,
- What do you want from me?! - I want you to be quiet,
这样我就不用用我的老二让你闭嘴了！
so I don't have to shut you up with my dick!
你，恶心的猪！
You, disgusting pig!
别让我开始，婊子! 有钱的女人是我的弱点
Don't get me started, bitch! Rich women are my weak spot.
来吧英雄,
Aw, c'mon, hero,
让我看看你是怎么做到的！
let me see how you do it!
当一个人不断被挑衅的时候，他怎么可能是好人呢？
How can a man be nice when he's constantly getting provoked?
怎么做? 告诉我怎么做？
How? Tell me how?
停下，塔宁! 停下！
Stop, Tane! Stop!
- 你怎么知道我在这里?-我不知道，快点！
- How did you know I was here? - I didn't. C'mon, quick!
- 那 Voyin 呢? 拜托!-他们要么把他的头砍下来,
- What about Voyin? Please! - They've either cut his head off,
- 或者要求赎金-我们无能为力
or are going to demand a ransom. There's nothing we can do.
朱基奇先生! 朱基奇先生！
Mr. Djukich! Mr. Djukich!
我希望你能理解
I hope you understand
你没资格对我们隐瞒真相
you're not in a position to hide the truth from us.
请回答奥伯迈斯特的问题
Please answer the Obermeister's questions.
我明白
I understand.
你有我们要求的东西
You have something we lay claim to.
我什么都没有了
I haven't got anything anymore.
没有? 那是谁的？
No? Then who has it?
一些项链在沃兰热将军那里
Some necklace is with General Vrangel.
他让我把这个给他
He asked me to give it to him.
是的然后呢？
Yes. And?
剩下的我还没看呢
I haven't seen the rest.
你怎么知道它的存在？
How do you know it exists?
沃兰赫尔要求的
Vrangel asked for it.
你拿到项链的时候它在哪儿？
Where was the necklace when it got to you?
在一个围栏里
In an enclosure.
没必要再折磨他了,
There's no need to torture him any further,
他说了他知道的一切
he said everything he knew.
我发誓，我就知道这么多！
I swear, that's all I know!
我发誓！
I swear!
朱基奇先生，冷静点
Mr. Djukich, calm down.
一切都会很快结束
Everything will be over quickly.
我们在天上的父，愿人都尊你的名为圣..
Our Father who art in heaven, hallowed be Thy name...